<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
  <title>Gabriel Cornish</title>
  <description>is loving the independent web</description>
  <link>https://gabrielcornish.com/</link>
  <atom:link href="https://gabrielcornish.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 07:59:01 -0800</lastBuildDate>
  <ttl>60</ttl>

<!-- ADD NEW POST HERE -->

  <item>
    <title>I'm making a game about exploring a small mall</title>
    <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Can I make my first Steam game in one year?</p>
<p>I&#39;ve always wanted to.</p>
<p>So, this year I started making a game about exploring a mall. In the game you buy gifts for friends, discover secrets, and meet other quirky shoppers.</p>
<p>I&#39;ve worked in the game industry for over 10 years, but I&#39;ve never released a Steam game on my own. It&#39;s been on my bucket list for a while, but never quite had the confidence to do it.</p>
<p>In some ways, I still don&#39;t.</p>
<p>Well, this year I chose to take a crack at it.</p>
<p>I&#39;m not one of those indies who&#39;s trying to strike it rich or make my &quot;dream&quot; game. Gambling in Las Vegas would be a more efficient way to make money.</p>
<p>No, I just want to make something that is worth charging for.</p>
<p>A game that&#39;s small, focused, and delivers a fun experience worth the asking price.</p>
<p>I want to <a href="https://gabrielcornish.com/posts/2025-02-23-What-Exactly-Is-a--Good--Game-.html">make small promises to my players</a>, and then fulfill them. Plus a little extra.</p>
<p>Nothing more. Nothing less.</p>
<p>I started prototyping the game in January and hope to release in January 2026.</p>
<p>I&#39;ll let you know how it goes.</p>
]]>
    </description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 07:59:01 -0800</pubDate>
    <link>https://gabrielcornish.com/posts/2025-02-25-I-m-making-a-game-about-exploring-a-small-mall.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">https://gabrielcornish.com/feed.xml#7</guid>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title></title>
    <description>
<![CDATA[<p>There&#39;s something that feels safe about a blog post. </p>
<p>It&#39;s cozy. </p>
<p>There&#39;s no algorithm to please.</p>
<p>It feels slower. Calmer. Thoughtful.</p>]]>
    </description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 11:24:26 -0800</pubDate>
    <link>https://gabrielcornish.com/feed.html?post=6</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">https://gabrielcornish.com/feed.xml#6</guid>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title></title>
    <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Friday nights in 2005:</p>
<ul>
<li>Vanilla Coke</li>
<li>Digiorno Supreme Pizza</li>
<li>Battlefront 2 (PS2) with friends</li>
</ul>
<p>Friday nights 2025:</p>
<ul>
<li>Ginger tea</li>
<li>Intermittent fasting</li>
<li>An episode of Ugly Betty with wife</li>
</ul>]]>
    </description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 16:58:20 -0800</pubDate>
    <link>https://gabrielcornish.com/feed.html?post=5</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">https://gabrielcornish.com/feed.xml#5</guid>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title></title>
    <description>
<![CDATA[<p>For those who love RSS as much as I do, definitely check out <a href="https://adamledoux.net/zoneRSS/">zoneRSS</a>. It&#39;s such a fun way to blog.</p>
]]>
    </description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 13:28:46 -0800</pubDate>
    <link>https://gabrielcornish.com/feed.html?post=4</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">https://gabrielcornish.com/feed.xml#4</guid>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title></title>
    <description>
<![CDATA[<p>I want the future of social media to just be RSS and email.</p>]]>
    </description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 11:20:46 -0800</pubDate>
    <link>https://gabrielcornish.com/feed.html?post=3</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">https://gabrielcornish.com/feed.xml#3</guid>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>What Exactly Is a "Good" Game?</title>
    <description>
<![CDATA[<p>I&#39;ve always struggled with the desire to make something that is considered &quot;good&quot;—and to do it consistently.</p>
<p>The problem is, &quot;good&quot; is subjective.</p>
<p>This led me to discover one of my toxic traits: I want the subjective to become objective. I&#39;m always searching for a reproducible and systematic approach to the creative process. I like things to be clear and straightforward.</p>
<p>It&#39;s flawed thinking, but I believed that if I could define what a good game was, then I could deconstruct the process and make one consistently.</p>
<p>A definition eluded me for a long time, but I eventually stumbled upon one that I feel good about:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A game is only as good as the promises it keeps.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I came across this idea in one of the best blog posts I’ve read on game creation: </p>
<p><a href="https://farawaytimes.blogspot.com/2023/02/how-to-make-good-small-games.html">How to Make Good Small Games.</a></p>
<p>After reading it, I realized that a game gets to define its own terms of success. It does this by making promises to the player—and then keeping them.</p>
<p>A game should be judged by how well it keeps its promises. Does it deliver what it says it will?</p>
<p>Making a game that costs half a billion dollars and takes ten years to develop is a type of promise with high expectations. It’s a hard promise to keep. Alternatively, a 5-minute game with amateur art can still be good as long as it delivers on its promises—a much easier promise to keep.</p>
<p>So, I think I’ve found a good balance between a subjective and objective definition of what makes a good game:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A good game keeps its promises to the player.</p>
</blockquote>
]]>
    </description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 11:17:15 -0800</pubDate>
    <link>https://gabrielcornish.com/posts/2025-02-23-What-Exactly-Is-a--Good--Game-.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">https://gabrielcornish.com/feed.xml#2</guid>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title></title>
    <description>
<![CDATA[<p>The structure of a fun game is simple.</p>
<p>Give the player a clear objective.</p>
<p>Reward them for their effort.</p>
<p>Tell them when they've achieved something.</p>]]>
    </description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 10:34:28 -0800</pubDate>
    <link>https://gabrielcornish.com/feed.html?post=1</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">https://gabrielcornish.com/feed.xml#1</guid>
  </item>

  

  <item>
    <title>A Daily Routine For Unemployed Game Devs</title>
    <description>
<![CDATA[<p>🕹 Unemployed as a game developer? Here's how I'm staying on track and keeping my spirits up.</p>
<p>I've crafted a simple daily routine that's been essential for my mental well-being and productivity during this period.</p>
<ul>
<li>Mornings: Create 🎨</li>
<li>Mid-days: Connect 📨</li>
<li>Afternoons: ​Contribute 🙌🏽</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="../images/unemployed-routine.jpg" alt="Unemployed Routine"></p>
<p><strong>CREATE</strong>: This is all about building skills and creative growth.</p>
<p>While the timing of my next opportunity is uncertain, I'm making the most of this time by exploring new technologies, building games, and honing my craft.</p>
<p><strong>CONNECT</strong>: This phase is all about maximizing opportunities.</p>
<p>Whether it's reaching out to my network, applying for roles, or sharing my latest work, I'm just trying to keep the momentum going.</p>
<p><strong>CONTRIBUTE</strong>: Giving back to the community is key.</p>
<p>Whether it's helping others in their job search, collaborating on indie projects, or participating in game jams, assisting others is how we're all going to get through this.</p>
<p>🌟 And here's one last bonus...</p>
<p><strong>EVENINGS</strong>: Community​ Evenings are dedicated to recharging with loved ones. It's my time to unplug, rest, and cherish moments with friends and family.</p>
<p>I'd love to hear what strategies have been working for you as you navigate your job search.</p>]]>
    </description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 21:22:13 -0800</pubDate>
    <link>https://gabrielcornish.com/posts/2025-02-22-A-Daily-Routine-For-Unemployed-Game-Devs.html</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">https://gabrielcornish.com/feed.xml#0</guid>
  </item>

</channel>
</rss>